<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Data Science N00b]]></title><description><![CDATA[Digital journal describing my career U-turn towards Data Science.]]></description><link>https://ekeleshian.github.io/</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 Jun 2018 21:24:45 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[From Math Teacher to Data Science n00b]]></title><description><![CDATA[I entered my late twenties questioning everything…  Moving to SF in 2016 caused some major turn arounds in my life. 
Various factors led…]]></description><link>https://ekeleshian.github.io//new-beginnings/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://ekeleshian.github.io//new-beginnings/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 10 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;I entered my late twenties questioning everything… &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moving to SF in 2016 caused some major turn arounds in my life.
Various factors led from one thing to the next, causing a sequence of events that
were so atypical compared to my prior way of life.  I can almost describe
my chain of events as spontaneous in a way; life has felt fast and exciting.
But with this spontaneity nature comes also a determined
side. Paradoxical, indeed, but the truth will always
hold that I have a deep affinity for math, especially statistics.
My dream has always been to find work where my math knowledge
puts me in an advantage and generates results that are impactful.&lt;br&gt;
Teaching middle school math somehow didn’t cut it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2016-2017 indeed has been an era of epiphanies.  Many realizations
were made that became game-changers in my life - one
being that I did not want to continue teaching.  Something very deep
in my instincts, a feeling that is too internal to describe in words,
could explain why teaching is ultimately not for me. This blog is not intended
to pour out those feelings.  This blog is just a representation of my
journal describing my progress as a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Newbie&quot;&gt;n00b&lt;/a&gt;
in data science.  &lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>